In this world, evil can arise
from the best of intentions.
この世界には
善意から生まれる悪意がある
And there is good which
can come from evil intentions.
悪意から生まれる善意がある
In which manner should
Lelouch's actions be taken?
ルルーシュが起こした行動は
果たしてどのように
受け止められるべきものなのか？
Is judgment inevitable in this world?
裁きは 世界の必然なのか
ギアス
Geass.
Those who use this
superhuman power...
この 人ならざる力を使う者は
will find their hearts isolated,
whether they want it or not,
否応なく心に孤独を作り出し
善意と悪意の狭間に落ち込んでいく
falling into the gap
between good and evil.
されど もし
But if there is someone who
can manage to climb out of it,
そこから立ち上がる者が
いるとするならば
そう
then that person has the potential to be a king.
その者は確かなる
王の器を手にしているのだろう
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
夢見てた夢
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
果て無き遠く
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・間隔の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
等身大 音をたてて
僕の顔　造って行く
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
この手に落ちた
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
腐りかけのリンゴ
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・感覚の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
頭身台 爪をたてて
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
僕の顔　削って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
－遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
CHEERING MAO
The first thing I want to confirm
is are you my enemy or my ally?
まず確認したい
お前は俺の敵か？　味方か？
何を今さら
What brings this up?
んん…
あのマオという男は
That man Mao has a Geass...
他人の考えを読み取る
ギアスを持っている
which allowed him to read other
peoples' thoughts. Am I correct?
それでいいのか？
そうだ
Correct. The manifestation of Geass
varies according to the individual.
ギアスの発現の仕方は人によって異なる
マオの場合は
In Mao's case, if he concentrates,
he can read thoughts up to 500 meters away.
集中すれば 最大500メートル先の
思考を読む事ができる
その気になれば
深層意識まで読み取れる
If he wants, he can even read
down to a person's subconscious.
頭で戦うタイプのお前には
最悪の敵だよ
For someone like you who fights using
his head, he's the worst possible enemy.
500メートル…
500 meters...
まぁ 想像はしていたがな
Still, I imagined this.
俺以外にもギアスを
使える奴がいるって事は
That there were others beside
me who could use Geass.
あいつもお前と契約したのか？
Did you make a contract with him?
11年前に
11 years ago.
はん 大先輩って訳だ
Heh, so, he's my great predecessor.
で？　その大先輩は俺の敵か？
So, is this great
predecessor my enemy?
マオの目的は私だ
敵とはいっても命を狙ったりは…
Mao's target is me. He may be your
enemy, but he's not out to kill you.
それは分かっている
I understand that.
だったらゼロの正体を
軍か警察に教えれば いいんだからな
A regular enemy could just reveal
Zero's identity to the army or the police.
なのにシャーリーにだけ…
Yet he only told Shirley...
What are the conditions on his power?
あいつの能力条件は？
マオのギアスは強い
Mao's Geass is powerful.
お前のように回数制限も
目を見るとかの制約も一切ない
Unlike you,
he has no restrictions on...
the number of times he can use
it or needing direct eye contact.
弱点はないのか？
He has no weaknesses, then?
強いてあげれば
マオは能力をオフにできない
If you must pin me down on one,
I'd say it's that Mao can't turn off his ability.
常に周囲の心の声が聞こえてしまう
He'll hear the thoughts of
everyone around him constantly.
本人が望もうと望むまいと
Whether he wants to or not...
このまま塾さぼっちゃおっかなぁ
Maybe I should blow
off cram school today.
Honestly, what a terrible racket!
やぁねぇ こんな所で騒いで
Yeah, I've gotta get that car. The red paint job is great.
いつになったら別れてくれるんだろう
Are those really Britannian students?
Yeah, I've gotta get that car. The red paint job is great.
バイトした方がいいかしら
They should be ashamed!
Yeah, I've gotta get that car. The red paint job is great.
うちの親も貴族だったらなあ
And look at how sloppy their uniforms are!
Yeah, I've gotta get that car. The red paint job is great.
くっ…
And look at how sloppy their uniforms are!
Everyone will call me The Comet!
結局 金 金 金…
It's getting worse lately,
Everyone will call me The Comet!
Racing down the road with the top down would be so cool!
くぁ…
with parents not raising their children properly!
Racing down the road with the top down would be so cool!
そろそろ帰ってもいい頃かな
くぅっ…
I never thought I'd be wasting my time...
Racing down the road with the top down would be so cool!
あー 腹減った
I never thought I'd be wasting my time...
I'll get the money somehow. When I get my next bonus...
なぜこの年になって
こんな所で時間潰ししなきゃならんのだ
...in a place like this at my age!
I'll get the money somehow. When I get my next bonus...
Should I tell my wife? But I can't say I quit my job!
今度は絶対当たる！
Well, I bought a hundred tickets this time,
I'll get the money somehow. When I get my next bonus...
くぅ…
so I'm sure to hit some money.
I understand, Mao. Don't worry, Mao.
分かってるよ マオ
安心しろ マオ
私は死にはしないさ
I'm not going to die. Mao! Mao!
マオ　マオ
起きたのか？　マオ
- Are you awake, Mao? Oh Mao, how silly of you!
- C.C., I can't live without you. Wait for me. I'm coming to see you now.
C.C.　やっぱり君じゃなくちゃあ
待ってて… 今 会いに行くよ
マオが俺の思考を読んだとすれば
If Mao could read my mind, then I imagine
he'll come after my weakest points.
俺の一番の急所を狙ってくるはずだが
お兄様と２人きりなんて久しぶり！
It's been so long since it's just
been the two of us around here.
咲世子さんにも
たまには休んでもらわないとな
Even Sayoko needs time off once in a while.
今日からは しばらく家にいるよ
Starting today, I'll be staying home for a while.
お兄様
最近家を空けてばかりでしたものね
You've just been out of the house so much lately.
何か面白い遊びでも見つけたんですか？
Have you found some sort of
really interesting game to play?
まぁね
今度の相手はちょっと手強くて
Sort of. My current opponent is pretty hard to beat.
あは
お兄様にそこまで言わせるなんて
どんな方でしょう？
I wonder what sort of person would
make you say something like that!
シュナイゼル兄様以来じゃないですか？
You haven't said that about anyone
since big brother Schneizel!
悪いけど許可証がないと売れないんでね
Sorry, but I can't sell you one without a permit.
Besides, you're from the
Chinese Federation, aren't you?
それに お客さん中華連邦でしょ？
へぇ
黒の騎士団には売っているのに？
Oh? Even though you sell
to the Black Knights?
あ！
先週の火曜 23時
相手の名前は… ウオルフ
Last Tuesday, 23:00 hours. Your contact
was named "Wolf." An alias, naturally.
もちろん偽名だけどね
あんた…
Who are you?!
都合してもらえるよねぇ？
You'll help me out, won't you?
With what I need.
いろいろと
それで？
And?
確かにお前の妹を守る事は必要だが
待っているだけでは…
I realize it's necessary to protect your
sister, but just waiting for him is!
黒の騎士団に探させている
I'm having the Black Knights look for him.
ゲットーではなく
このトウキョウ租界にいたらどうする？
What if he's here in the Tokyo
settlement and not the ghetto?
時間の無駄遣いだ
It'll be a waste of time.
そんな事より私をおとりに使え
You should use me as bait instead.
マオの目的は私だ　私が…
I'm Mao's target, so I should be...
Tell me, if I keep on using my
Geass, will I become like him?
なあ ギアスを使い続けると
俺も ああなるのか？
あっ…
それとも
Or did it happen because he
didn't fulfill his contract with you?
お前との契約を果たさなかったから
ああなったのか？
使ううちに
ギアスはその力を増していく
With each use, the power
of your Geass will increase.
克服できない者は
自らの力そのものに飲み込まれていく
Those who can't control their
power will be consumed by it.
それを知ってて
契約を持ちかけたのか！
And knowing that, you still made these
contracts?! With me? And with Mao?
俺にも マオにも！
そうだ
I did.
ひどい女だ
You're a cruel woman. I can't imagine
why anyone would be after you.
追いかける奴の気が知れないな
Did you abandon Mao because
he couldn't fulfill his contract?
マオは契約を果たせなかった
だから捨てたのか？
契約の内容は？
What are the details of the contract?!
んん…
お前は卑劣だ！
You disgust me!
ああっ…
捨てる時になぜ始末しなかった？
Why didn't you take care of him
when you abandoned him?!
力を奪うなり 命を奪うなり
Take his power back, or take his life?!
その中途半端のせいでシャーリーは！
Because you left things
half-finished, Shirley was!
マオに関しては
別行動を取るべきだろうな
We need to split up to deal with Mao.
今日から隣の棟に移る
Starting today,
I'll stay in the tower next door.
隣？
Next door? That's where the student
council and the cultural club meet.
生徒会や文化部の部室が…
そんな事は知らん
I don't care.
I'll leave you to deal with it.
後処理はそっちで何とかしろ
ううう…
メディカルチェック？
A medical check?
ナイトメアのパイロットには
義務付けられているの
It's compulsory for all Knightmare pilots.
分かりました
I see.
じゃ 明日 学校が終わったら
All right, then see you tomorrow after school.
はい
Right. Oh, Miss Cecile, is there any way
I could meet with Princess Euphemia?
ああ セシルさん
ユーフェミア皇女殿下に
会う方法って ありますか？
え？　会いたいの？
Oh? You want to meet her?
無理でしょ
Forget it. You need to be a Knight of
Honor at least to get an audience with her.
謁見は騎士候位 以上だからねぇ
伯爵閣下なら
おできになるんじゃありません？
Can't an earl do something?
僕？
Me?
ええ
Yes.
は？
ロイドさんって…
伯爵だったんですか？
Lloyd, you're an earl?!
あはははは
いやあ お恥ずかしい
Oh, I'm so embarrassed!
放蕩貴族よ
遊びと仕事の区別がついていないの
He's a prodigal aristocrat.
He can't differentiate between work and play.
はあ…
数日でいいんです
Just for a few days.
しばらくの間
If you can just keep the club house off limits...
クラブハウスを
立ち入り禁止にしてもらえれば
そりゃあ できない事はないけど…
It's not like I can't do it, but...
ねぇ まさか皇子だって事…
No one's found out you're a prince, have they?
バレてませんよ
I haven't been revealed.
俺が生きてる事を知ってるのは
アッシュフォード家だけですから
Only the Ashford family knows I'm still alive.
Ashford, huh...
アッシュフォードねぇ
ん？
どうかしました？
Something wrong?
ルルーシュ
Lelouch, they've set me up
to meet another suitor.
あたし ま～たお見合い
今度は逃げられないかも
I may not be able to get out of this one.
What do you think I should do?
ねぇ どうすればいっかなぁ？
いや… それは…
Well, that's...
会長～！
Ms. President!
あ！
シャーリー？　朝練復活すんの？
Shirley? Were you back at morning practice?
はい　今日からまた
落ち込んでても しょうがないし
Yeah. Just started again today.
No point in staying sad forever!
あは
私も見習おっかなぁ？　あんたの行動力
I should take lessons
from your positive attitude.
なぁに言ってるんですか？
会長の方が…
Oh, what are you talking about?
You're just as...
あれ？
Oh?
あなた この間の
You're the boy from...
You go to this school, too?
うちの学校だったんだ！
何ふざけてんの？
Are you kidding?
同じクラスだろ？
We're in the same class.
え？　そんなはず…
What?! I don't think so...
んん？
Hm... Huh?
あれ？
もういいだろ？
Enough.
シャーリー！　始まっちゃうよぉ
Shirley, it's starting!
今 行く！
Coming! See you, Prez!
じゃ 会長 また！
うん
Right...
今の何？
What was all that just now?
ちょっと… 喧嘩して
We had a little fight.
で 他人ごっこ？
かわいいプレイだねぇ
She's acting like she doesn't know you?
What an adorable play!
悪いけど合わせてくれますか？
ほとぼりが冷めるまで
Sorry, but can you play along
with it? Until she cools down.
ま いいけどさぁ　長引きそう？
Sure, I guess so.
Think it'll be a while?
ええ 多分
Yeah. I think so.
ぐおぅっ
探しているのは
リフレインの売人じゃない
I'm not looking for a Refrain dealer!
マオという東洋人だと言っただろ！
I said it was an Asian named Mao, didn't I?!
租界で東洋人って言ったら
あとは下働きしかいねぇよお！
The only Asians in the
settlement are day laborers!
警察にでも行けってえ…
Why not ask the cops?!
警察は嫌いだ！
I don't like cops!
じゃあ… 黒の騎士団に頼みな
Then ask the Black Knights for help!
裏ルートなら租界もゲットーも
今は あそこが一番強い
They're the best to go to for black market
routes in the settlement and the ghettos!
That's all everyone tells me!
どいつもこいつも 同じ答えを！
当たり前だろ！
Because it's obvious!
くっ
ええっ あれ おっかしいなぁ
Huh? That's strange.
なんで？
What happened?
さっきから何探してんの？
What have you been looking for?
日記　私の 見つかんなくって…
My diary. I can't seem to find it.
ええ？　外に持ってったとか？
Oh? Did you take it out?
まぁさか
No way!
はい　申し訳ありません ゼロ
マオという男は未だ
Right. I'm sorry, Zero.
We haven't found that Mao guy yet.
そうか
I see.
キョウトの情報網も使いますか？
Should we use Kyoto's
information network, too?
いや　関東ブロックだけでいい
網にかかったら私に連絡を
No, just keep it to the Kanto block.
If you net anything, contact me.
分かっています
Understood.
では また定時に
All right, I'll contact you
again at the regular time.
500メートル以内に入れば
マオに心を読まれてしまう
Mao can read my mind
if I get within 500 meters.
しかし それが逆に
あいつの手を読む条件になるのだが
But conversely, that condition
may let me predict his actions.
チッ　ええぃっ！
チェックをかけるには 駒が１枚…
It's like having one piece
to move to check him!
足りないか？
Out of ideas?
どうやら考える事は同じだな
No matter how you think about it,
you come up with the same thing.
そうらしいな
It seems that way.
我々は協力できると思うが？
Do you think we can work together?
ああ
Yes.
ん？
ふん
はい
Yes?
僕だよ　ルル
It's me, Lulu!
そこにいるんだろ？　C.C.
And C.C. is there, isn't she?
I want to talk to her alone. Put her on.
２人っきりで話したいんだ
代わってよ
ん…
気がついたか？
You're awake?
はい
Yes?
どうして あんな所に倒れていたんだ？
Why were you collapsed in that place?
君の名前は？
What's your name?
私…
My... My name?
名前？
え？
なんだろう？
What is it?
まさか 記憶が…
ゼロの事は？　お前は あの時！
Don't tell your memory is...
What about Zero?!
When I found you, you said!
ゼロって？
Who's Zero?
あっ うっ！
何やってるんだ 俺は…
What the hell am I doing?!
I practically betray him, and now this?!
裏切るような真似までして このざまか
だって… 分からないのよ
But I don't know!
うっ！
何も…
Nothing...
すまない　あ その…
Sorry. I was able to undress you with
my eyes closed, but dressing you...
脱がせるのは目をつむっても
できたんだが　着せるのは…
でも… 部屋も暖かくしたから
大丈夫かと
But this room's warm,
so I figured you'd be all right.
ふぅ 良かった
Thank goodness.
え？
とりあえず
いい人に拾ってもらったみたい
At the very least, it looks like
I was picked up by a good man.
はあ？
うふ
喜べ ルルーシュ
私とお前はここでお別れだ
Be happy, Lelouch.
This is where you and I say goodbye.
ん！
私はマオとやり直す事にした
I've made up with Mao.
裏切るのか？
You're betraying me?
何を今さら
What are you saying now?
私は お前と仲間だったつもりはない
ただの共犯者だ
I never considered us to be friends.
Just co-conspirators.
待て！
Wait!
これは驚きだ
それではマオと同じだなあ
This is surprising.
You're acting just like Mao.
C.C.　お前は俺の事を知りすぎている
C.C....
You know too much about me.
このまま行かせる訳にはいかない
I can't just let you go like this.
行くな　俺の所にいろ！　C.C.
Don't go! Stay here with me, C.C.!
ふっ
私にギアスは効かない　言っただろ？
Geass doesn't work on me.
I told you, didn't I?
ぬ！
安心しろ
お前の事をしゃべるつもりはない
Relax.
I won't tell him about you.
ギアスもそのままだ
You'll keep your Geass.
マオだって
もう二度とお前の前には現れない
Mao will never cross your path again.
これで障壁は なくなった
Now your obstacle has gone away.
おめでとう　さようなら
Congratulations, and goodbye.
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
テストの結果は良好よ
The test results were good,
規律と生命の項目に関しては
ちょっと数値が高すぎるみたいだけど
although it looks like your results pertaining
to discipline and life are a bit too high.
問題に なりますか？
Will that cause a problem for me?
優秀よ　軍人としては
They're excellent for a soldier.
あなた無意識のうちに
お父さんと自分を比較してない？
Do you think that, subconsciously,
you compare yourself to your father?
え？
それがあなたを
規定しているのかもしれないわ
That may be what's ruling you.
著名な親を持った子供には
よくある事なの
It's quite common in the children of famous people.
枢木玄武 元日本国首相
Genbu Kururugi, the former prime minister.
I understand he was a great man.
立派な方だったそうね
M
E
O
R
I
A
L
T
O
遅いなあ 卜部達
それにしても
皮肉な待ち合わせ場所ですね
By the way, this is an ironic
meeting place, don't you think?
枢木首相の慰霊碑とは
The memorial for Prime Minister Kururugi.
徹底抗戦を唱えていたのに
真っ先に自決した売国奴
The guy who told us to fight to the end, then
betrayed us all by committing suicide first.
よせ！
Stop that. You may as well be denying
General Katase, who also committed suicide.
それ以上は 自決された
片瀬少将をも否定する事になるぞ
潜伏中の藤堂を発見
Fugitive Tohdoh, identified.
All units, prepare to apprehend.
各班 確保準備
イエス マイ・ロード
Yes, my lord.
読ませてもらったよ
黒の騎士団の再編案
I had a look at the plan to
reorganize the Black Knights.
いくつか修正して欲しい部分はあるが
おおむね理解した
There are a few parts I'd like to improve,
but I generally get the idea.
君の考えは扇にも通しておこう
I'll run your idea by Ohgi, too.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
群れとしての細胞の機能予想図を
I'd like you to add a
chart that forecasts how...
ネクストテイクには
入れ込んでもらいたい
all the cells function as a group in
the next version. We'll talk later.
では
最終テストという訳か
The final test, is that it?
ディートハルト
Diethard...
ブリタニア人だが
予想以上に使えそうだな
He's Britannian, but he's proving
even more useful than I expected.
まだスパイの可能性は排除しきれないが
I can't yet eliminate the
possibility that he's a spy, but...
あ…
そうか　マオの電話
I see. That call from Mao...
あ…
C.C.
C.C.! You're so quiet!
君は なんて静かなんだ！
君の心だけは読めないよ
Your mind is the only one I can't read!
やっぱり君は最高だよ
You really are the best there is!
相変わらず子供だな
As childish as ever, I see.
白馬の王子って言って欲しいなあ
I'd like you to call me your
prince on a white horse!
君を迎えに来たんだからさ
I came here for you, after all.
ははははは
嬉しいだろ？　C.C.
Aren't you happy, C.C.?
マオ　前にも言ったはずだ
Mao, didn't I tell you before?
You and l...
私はお前とは…
そんなの 嘘 嘘
Oh, you were just kidding then!
C.C.は僕の事 大好きなんだから
You love me, after all!
ありがとう マオ
Thank you, Mao. Mao. Mao.
マオ　マオ
やめろ！
Stop!
うるさぁぁーい！
BE QUIET!!!
気にするな　私の声だけに耳を傾けて
Relax. Just listen to my voice alone.
うう…
そうだ
That's it.
私の心だけが聞こえないのなら
Since my mind is the only one you can't
read and you're only calm when we're alone,
２人っきりでいる時だけ
落ち着けるのなら
私はいつもお前の傍にいる
then I'll stay with you always.
ああ
Yes...
私はここにいる
I'm right here.
だから安心して
Be at ease.
C.C.　君だけだ
C.C., you're the only one!
君だけなんだ 僕が欲しいのは
You're all that I want!
ルルーシュなんて どうでもいい
君さえ来てくれれば
I don't care about Lelouch,
as long as you come with me.
Stop it!
やめろ！
ひ！
最初から こうしておくべきだったんだ
I should have done this
from the start!
僕だよ C.C.
It's me, C.C....
マオ
Mao.
クロヴィスランドで待っている
１人で来て
I'll be waiting at Clovisland.
Come alone.
はっ 相変わらず一方的だな
You're as selfish as ever, I see.
来てくれないんなら
ルルーシュの正体をバラすだけだよ？
If you don't come, I just have to
reveal Lelouch's identity, don't I?
彼を抹殺するのは
いつでも できるんだけど
I can have him eliminated at any time.
喜べ ルルーシュ
私とお前はここでお別れだ
Be happy, Lelouch.
This is where you and I say goodbye.
全く
勝手に戻って来たり 出て行ったり
For God's sake, just coming
and going as she pleases...
一方的な女は理解しづらいな
It's hard to understand such a selfish girl.
バカが！
Idiot!
う…
やっぱりC.C.は僕を撃てなかった
I knew you wouldn't
be able to shoot me!
C.C.は僕が好きなんだよ
You love me, after all, C.C.!
あはははは…
違う！　私はお前を利用しただけだ！
You're wrong! I was just using you!
何 言ってんの？
嘘はいけないよ 嘘は
What are you saying?
You shouldn't lie, you know.
うわ！
嘘はダメなんだよ
Lies are very, VERY naughty!
嘘は！
う！
あうっ！　うっ！
心配しないで
Don't you worry.
Because I understand!
僕は分かっているから
う…
C.C. 僕ねえ
C.C., I've built a house in Australia.
オーストラリアに家を建てたんだ
白くて綺麗なとても静かな家
A clean, white, very quiet little house.
う…
だけど オーストラリアに行くには
飛行機に乗らなくちゃいけないんだ
But we'll need to take an
airplane to get to Australia.
でもC.C.を飛行機に持ち込むには
ちょっと大きすぎる
And you're a little too big for
me to bring on a plane, C.C....
うう…
だからさあ…
So, you see...
コンパクトにしてあげる
I'll make you nice and compact!
It'll take no time at all with this!
これなら あっという間だよ！
罰のつもりか？　私への…
This is...
vengeance on me?
違うよ　違う 違う 違う 違う
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, NO!
違うんだよ
これは感謝の気持ちだよ
This is me expressing my gratitude to you!
やはり そこにいたか
So this is where you are.
ん？
他人の声が邪魔にならない場所
おのずと位置は絞り込まれるな
Someplace where the voices
of others wouldn't bother you.
That naturally narrowed it to a few places.
ルルーシュ
Lelouch!
うあ…
お前のギアスの有効範囲は
最大500メートル
The maximum range of your Geass is 500 meters.
このトウキョウタワーまでは届かない
It won't reach me here on Tokyo Tower.
ははっ
確かに 確かに
Indeed! Indeed!
でもねぇ それで どうするつもり？
Still, what do you plan to do?
いろいろとハッキングして
頑張っちゃったみたいだけど
After all the effort you
spent hacking this system,
他のおもちゃも遠隔操作して
僕を襲わせるのかな？
do you plan to attack me
with remote-controlled toys?
それとも その達者な口で
僕を言い負かすの？
Or will you use that skillful mouth
of yours to talk me into a defeat?
おーい 今度はダンマリかい？
What, has the cat got your tongue?
C.C.が欲しいのならお前も…
Even if you want C.C.,
then why don't you...
マオ　お前まさか C.C.というのが
Mao!
Surely you don't think that
C.C. is her real name, do you?
本当の名前だと
思ってるんじゃないだろうな？
ん？
は…
俺は知っている　本当の名前をな
I know it, though. Her real name...
そうなの？　C.C.
僕には教えてくれなかったのに
Is that true, C.C.?
Even though you never told it to me?
Why did you tell someone like him?!
どうしてあんな奴に…
分かっただろ？
C.C.は この俺のものだ
You know why, don't you?
Because C.C. belongs to me.
C.C.はもう 俺のものなんだよ　マオ
C.C. belongs to me, Mao.
違う！
She doesn't!
違う 違う 違う 違う 違う 違う！
She doesn't, she doesn't, she doesn't,
she doesn't, she doesn't, SHE DOESN'T!
ずっと前から僕だけのC.C.だったんだ！
She was all mine long before she ever met you!
俺はC.C.の全てを手に入れた
I have gained everything of her.
お前が見た事もない部分も含めて
Including all the parts you have never seen.
う！
全て
Everything...
ルルーシュ！
Lelouch!!!!
出て来い！　ルルーシュ！
Face me!
LELOUCH!
Come to me! Come into me!
I'll look inside you and see for myself!
こっちに来い　僕の中に来い！
お前を覗き見てやる！
このぉ！　嘘つきー！
Damn you! Liar!
マオ　お前の負けだ
Mao... You've lost.
何 言ってるんだ！
- What are you saying?! Never mind! I'm taking C.C. and...
もういい　僕はC.C.と…
- Just some guy acting up.
- What are you saying?! Never mind! I'm taking C.C. and...
Shouldn't be in the park, anyway.
うっ…
Must just be some Eleven junkie.
どうせ…
What's wrong with me?
むしゃむしゃ…
Just wasting our time...
俺だって中山ささえに会いたいんだ…
- Nervous?
- No, I'm just excited.
大丈夫…
Don't freak out. It'll be okay.
Number of hostages, unknown.
ルルーシュか？
You've trained for this again and again.
Number of hostages, unknown.
でも 距離が…
You've trained for this again and again.
Gotta move fast.
行動するんだ…
Just see the situation and act.
Gotta move fast.
And in an amusement park of all places?
それに…
いっぱい？
Gotta be a nut...
Hold it right there!
Drop the weapon and surrender!
そこまでだ！
武器を捨て 投降せよ！
う… なんだよ あいつら
What are they doing here?!
うあ…
誘拐犯に告げる！
Attention kidnapper!
Drop your weapon and surrender!
武器を捨て 投降せよ！
け… 警察？
The... The police?!
Who tipped them off?!
誰だ 通報したのは？
うっ
あ…
ルルーシュ　なぜここに？
Lelouch!
What are you doing here?
It can't be! He was just
at the Tower, wasn't he?!
嘘だ！　だってさっきまで
タワーにいたじゃないか！
お前 バカか？
Are you an idiot?
That was all a recording.
録画だよ　今までのは
嘘だ！
That's not true! I mean...
You were talking to me!
だって… だって
しゃべってたじゃないか 僕と！
お前の思考はシンプルすぎる
心を読めるのが仇になったな
Your thoughts are far too simple.
Your mind reading is a crutch now.
You were able to predict all my answers?!
Don't play games with me, you little punk!
僕の答えまで予想できたってぇのか？
ふざけんな　このガキ！
警察に捕まってもな
すぐ出てきてやる！
- If I'm getting caught by the cops, I'll get out soon!
何 言ってんだ？
- Shut up, Mr. Chainsaw! You're not fooling anybody!
- If I'm getting caught by the cops, I'll get out soon!
独り言？
狂ってんのかよ？
Just drop the weapon,
nice and slow.
He's desperate.
He belongs in a hospital.
おかしくなってるな
武器を下ろせ
Does he think he's talking to someone?
He belongs in a hospital.
I don't what drove him to this, but what he's done here is just as sad.
通報どおり
リフレイン中毒っぽいな
うるさい　僕の悪口を言うなー！
Shut up! Stop making fun of me!
ふっ C.C.が教えてくれたよ
おまえはギアスをオフにできない
C.C. told me.
You can't turn your Geass off.
しかし 有効範囲は集中力次第
However, your range depends on
how much you're concentrating.
僕の気をそらす為にモニターを使った？
You used the monitor to keep me distracted?
でもな… 僕にはまだ
お前に勝つ方法があるんだよ！
Even so, there's still one thing
I can do to make sure you lose!
それをやった時が お前の最後だ
The moment you do it
will be the moment you die.
Lelouch, wait! If I talk to him...
待ってくれ ルルーシュ
ちゃんと話せば！
何が最後だ！
Like hell I'll die!
ポリスども よーく聞け！
そこにいる奴がテロリストのー！
Listen up, cops!
That guy over there is the terrorist...
撃て！
Fire!
マオ！
Mao!
あ… ああ…
ゼロ…
Zero!
契約した時
マオはたった６歳で 孤児だった
Mao was only 6 years old when I made
my contract with him. An orphan.
読み書きも 親の愛情も 善悪も
何も知らなかった
How to read and write, the love of a parent,
good and evil... He knew none of that.
こちらエコースリー
予定通りゲットーにて人質を解放した
This is Echo-3. Hostage has been
released in the ghetto, as planned.
何？　病院への搬送はどうする…
What? What about your orders
to take her to the hospital...
私が与えたギアスの力は
マオから人を遠ざけた
The Geass power I gave to
Mao drove people from him.
だから私は マオの親友で 恋人で
And so I became his best friend, his lover...
While I was still just a stranger.
他人だった
私だけがマオにとっての人間だった
I was the only one Mao thought of
as a person. I was his entire world.
世界の全てだったんだ
C.C.
C.C.... I'm not going to lose to my Geass.
俺はギアスに負けたりはしない
この力を支配して使いこなしてみせる
I'm going to control this power
and try to manage it.
この世界を変えてみせる
I'm going to try and change this world.
俺の願いも お前の願いも
まとめて叶えてみせる
I'll try and fulfill both
your wish and my own.
奴に果たせなかった契約を
俺は実現してやる
I'll realize the contract which he
was unable to fulfill. So, please...
だから…
ルルーシュ
Lelouch.
あっ
慰めか？　哀れみか？　それとも…
Is this you comforting me?
Taking pity? Or is it... obsession?
執着か？
契約だ　今度は 俺からお前への
It's a contract.
This time, from me to you.
いいだろう
Very well. I accept your contract.
結ぼう　その契約
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
意味もなく繰り返し
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
過去の嘘も過ちも
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
振り返れば
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
今は進む時
Now is the time to move forward!
To meet Cornelia and get the truth!
コーネリアに会い 真実を問いただす
そして ナナリーの居場所も作り出す
And to make a place
for Nunnally in this world.
もはや 小さな戦場に意味はない
These tiny battlefields
are meaningless now!
トウキョウ租界を制圧してやる
I have to take control
of the Tokyo settlement!
その為には軍事力を増強し
外部勢力も利用する
For that, we need to build up our military
force and use external force as well.
使える駒は全て使って
NUNNALLY HELD HOSTAGE
We'll use everything
that can be used!